Inventory of the Theodore Fred Abel papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- List of Individuals
  - #459: Hedwig Eggert, birthdate: 1897, number of pages: 11
  - #460: Hans Borgwardt, birthdate: 1879, World War I service: 1916-1918, Nazi party number: 99803, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #461: Willy Diebel, birthdate: 1879, Nazi party number: 1352, number of pages: 2
  - #462: Erich Götze, birthdate: 1896, World War I service: 1914-1916, number of pages: 2
  - #463: Gerhard Tarcow, birthdate: 1899, World War I service: from 1917, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #464: Franz Jahnke, birthdate: 1906, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #465: Werner K., birthdate: 1907, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #466: Heinz Bock, birthdate: 1905, Nazi party number: 92639, number of pages: 5 (typed)
  - #467: Albrecht Leman, birthdate: 1895, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #468: Theodor ?, birthdate: 1903, Nazi party number: 297037, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #469: Willi Rostel, birthdate: 1903, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #470: Johann Pantenburg, birthdate: 1898, number of pages: 2
  - #471: Wilhelm Zander, birthdate: 1915, number of pages: 2
  - #472: Georg Ahlemann, birthdate: 1911, number of pages: 6
  - #473: A. Maringer, birthdate: 1891, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 6
  - #474: Magnus Maier, birthdate: 1900, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #475: Adolf Hofmann, birthdate: circa 1900, World War I service: 1918, Nazi party number: 58393, number of pages: 6
  - #476: Wilhelm Trapp, birthdate: 1902, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #477: Hermann Thomas, birthdate: 1909, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #478: Wolfgang ?, birthdate: 1916, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #479: Georg M., birthdate: 1914, number of pages: 2
  - #480: missing
  - #481: Hans Dimold, birthdate: 1909, number of pages: 5
  - #482: Willhelm Muller, birthdate: 1905, number of pages: 2
  - #483: Martin L., birthdate: 1907, number of pages: 2
  - #484: Richard Hermann, birthdate: 1900, World War I service: 1918, number of pages: 4
  - #485: unknown, birthdate: 1910, number of pages: 3
  - #486: Paul Schwerdtner, birthdate: 1899, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 3
  - #487: Gustav Grahlow, birthdate: 1901, number of pages: 7
  - #488: Arthur ?, birthdate: 1907, number of pages: 7
  - #489: A. Meister, birthdate: 1900, number of pages: 5
  - #490: Karl Kell, birthdate: 1903, number of pages: 3
  - #491: Erwin ?, birthdate: 1907, number of pages: 1
  - #492: Johann Köhler, birthdate: 1907, number of pages: 4
  - #493: Friedrich W. Kell, birthdate: 1895, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #494: Siegfried Klein, birthdate: 1911, number of pages: 2
  - #495: unknown, birthdate: 1902, number of pages: 4
  - #496: Gustav Niemzick, birthdate: 1872, World War I service: unknown, Nazi party number: 15573, number of pages: 3 (not typed)
  - #497: Fritz H., birthdate: 1908, number of pages: 1
  - #498: Fritz Nagel, birthdate: 1911, number of pages: 1
  - #499: Fritz Rösoiowsky, birthdate: 1893, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 2
  - #500: Gustav Ronacker, birthdate: 1892, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 4
  - #501: Otto Dellnitz, birthdate: 1885, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #502: August Spanku, birthdate: 1898, World War I service: from 1917, Nazi party number: 331715, number of pages: 3 (not typed)
  - #503: Otto Hallstein, birthdate: 1895, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 2
  - #504: Franz Laborius, birthdate: 1888, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 1
  - #505: Hugo L., birthdate: 1896, World War I service: 1914-1918, Nazi party number: 295273, number of pages: 1
  - #506: Max N., birthdate: 1903, number of pages: 1
  - #507: Koller, birthdate: 1902, Nazi party number: 366169, number of pages: 1
  - #508: Oskar Hollatz, birthdate: 1902, Nazi party number: 295224, number of pages: 1
  - #509: G., birthdate: 1912, number of pages: 2
  - #510: Eduard Kreil, birthdate: 1884, World War I service: 1914-1920, Nazi party number: 206509, number of pages: 2
  - #511: Wilhelm Kallweit, birthdate: 1872, World War I service: from 1915, number of pages: 1
  - #512: Friedrich Kupsch, birthdate: 1898, World War I service: from 1917, number of pages: 2
  - #513: Günther Lipske, birthdate: 1887, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3
  - #514: Kurt Daum, birthdate: 1889, World War I service: 1914-1918, Nazi party number: 96184, number of pages: 1 (typed)
  - #515: Josef Krause, birthdate: 1898, World War I service: from 1917, number of pages: 5 (not typed)
  - #516: Wolfgang Müller, birthdate: 1901, Nazi party number: 522022, number of pages: 2
  - #517: Walter Szimba, birthdate: 1902, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #518: Matthes Löffler, birthdate: 1874, number of pages: 4 (not typed)
  - #519: Hugo F., birthdate: 1895, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 2
  - #520: Wilhelm Berzym, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 1 (typed)
  - #521: Ferdinand Arnold, birthdate: 1902, Nazi party number: 89553, number of pages: 2
  - #522: Erich Schumski, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, Nazi party number: 462501, number of pages: 3
  - #523: Johann Klaassen, birthdate: 1886, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 2
  - #524: August ?, birthdate: 1887, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3
  - #525: Willy Unger, birthdate: 1901, number of pages: 10 (not typed)
  - #526: Fritz Junghanss, birthdate: circa 1900, World War I service: 1918, number of pages: 5 (typed)
  - #527: Wilhelm Götze, birthdate: 1893, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 8
  - #528: August H. Hofer, birthdate: 1868, Nazi party number: 249733, number of pages: 9
  - #529: Richter, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 12 (not typed)
  - #530: Heinz Goldgruber, birthdate: 1914, number of pages: 5
  - #531: Rudolf Freimann, birthdate: 1890, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #532: Erika Ullmann, birthdate: unknown, number of pages: 5
  - #533: Heinrich Brüssler, birthdate: 1911, number of pages: 5
  - #534: Alfred Buchholz, birthdate: 1902, Nazi party number: 69186, number of pages: 16
  - #535: Georg Hauser, birthdate: 1885, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 3 (not typed)
  - #536: Adolf Junck, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, Nazi party number: 99821, number of pages: 2
  - #537: Otto Lenart, birthdate: after 1900, Nazi party number: 477433, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #538: Bruno Tschiesche, birthdate: 1875, Nazi party number: 743684, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #539: Hugo Resling, birthdate: 1891, World War I service: unknown, Nazi party number: 48336, number of pages: 10
  - #540: Jaro Fischer, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 6
  - #541: Valentin Boenke, birthdate: 1887, World War I service: 1915-1918, Nazi party number: 154193, number of pages: 4
  - #542: Friedrich Becker, birthdate: 1872, number of pages: 3
  - #543: Paul Rothe, birthdate: 1892, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3
  - #544: Georg Spör?, birthdate: before 1900, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3
  - #545: Hoffmann, birthdate: 1898, World War I service: 1917-1919, number of pages: 2
  - #546: Schmidt, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #547: Klara L., birthdate: 1883, Nazi party number: 5653, number of pages: 5 (not typed)
  - #548: Heinrich Bauder, birthdate: 1881, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 4
  - #549: Georg Lauermann, birthdate: 1904, number of pages: 9
  - #550: Hermann Kreye, birthdate: 1910, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #551: Theodor Strumpf, birthdate: 1884, World War I service: 1914-1915, Nazi party number: 29820, number of pages: 4
  - #552: Johannes E. Knust, birthdate: 1888, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 4
  - #553: Walther v. Marck, birthdate: 1882, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 4 (not typed)
  - #554: Ernst-Paul Hempel, birthdate: 1883, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 3
  - #555: A. Rahmul, birthdate: 1904, number of pages: 3
  - #556: Gerhard Kramer, birthdate: after 1900, Nazi party number: 93715, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #557: Georg Sturmhoevel, birthdate: 1900, number of pages: 5 (not typed)
  - #558: Hugo Schölzki, birthdate: 1905, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #559: Albert Lenz, birthdate: after 1900, Nazi party number: 215265, number of pages: 3
  - #560: Ludwig Aubel, birthdate: before 1890, number of pages: 1 (not typed)
  - #561: Eduard Frei, birthdate: unknown, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #562: Karl Schotten, birthdate: 1899, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 2 (not typed)
  - #563: Klaus Schmidt, birthdate: 1898, World War I service: from 1916, number of pages: 4 (typed)
  - #564: Eduard Egert, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 3 (not typed)
  - #565: Friedrich ?, birthdate: 1899, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 2
  - #566: Johann Schrhag, birthdate: 1904, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #567: Rudolf Gehring, birthdate: 1893, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 6 (not typed)
  - #568: Ernst ?, birthdate: 1913, number of pages: 3
  - #569: unknown, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 3
  - #570: Theo Hagemann, birthdate: 1912, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #571: H. Heckmann, birthdate: 1891, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 3 (not typed)
  - #572: Heinrich Gölz, birthdate: 1895, World War I service: unknown, number of pages: 3
  - #573: Helmuth de Sail, birthdate: after 1900, Nazi party number: 5651845, number of pages: 7
  - #574: Gertrud Michael, birthdate: unknown, Nazi party number: 1400825, number of pages: 3 (typed)
  - #575: Max Rudolph, birthdate: 1883, World War I service: from 1917, number of pages: 8
  - #576: Werner Kauffmann, birthdate: 1896, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 17 (not typed)
  - #577: Herbert Sorge, birthdate: 1911, number of pages: 10
  - #578: Alfred Oppermann, birthdate: 1878, World War I service: 1914-1918, number of pages: 15 (typed)
  - #579: Georg Witt, birthdate: 1889, World War I service: from 1916, number of pages: 18
  - #580: missing
  - #581: Karl Keil, birthdate: 1899, World War I service: 1918, number of pages: 2
  - #582: Margarethe Schrimpff, birthdate: 1880, Nazi party number: 91227, number of pages: 13
  - #583: Roland Schoenfelder, birthdate: 1903, number of pages: 8
  - #584: Emil Groh, birthdate: 1887, World War I service: 1917-1918, number of pages: 3
  - #585: Kurt Stern, birthdate: 1910, number of pages: 9
  - #586: August Zimmermann, birthdate: unknown, World War I service: 1916-1918, number of pages: 2
  - #587: Albert Wiechert, birthdate: 1882, World War I service: 1914-1918, Nazi party number: 28470, number of pages: 3
  - #588: Klara Petersson, birthdate: 1892, number of pages: 12 (not typed)
  - #589: Therese Diebel, birthdate: 1887, Nazi party number: 743162, number of pages: 4
  - #590: Arthur Herrmann, birthdate: 1898, World War I service: from 1917, Nazi party number: 1090228, number of pages: 2 (typed)
  - #591: Josef Rantle, birthdate: 1872, World War I service: unknown, Nazi party number: 40821/334399, number of pages: 4 (not typed)
  - #592: Heinz Mai, birthdate: 1907, Nazi party number: 76236, number of pages: 14 (typed)
  - #593: Gerhard Hinzes, birthdate: 1911, number of pages: 3 (not typed)
- List of Women
  For microfilm reel numbers, see Nazi Biograms series.
  - #30: Maria Bauer, number of pages: 5
  - #36: Hertha von Reuss, number of pages: 3
  - #41: Marlene Heder and sister, number of pages: 8
  - #44: Hilde Boehm-Stoltz, number of pages: 5
  - #46: Grete Kirchner, number of pages: 3
  - #100A: Agnes Mosler-Sturm, number of pages: 5
  - #107: Lissy Schneider, number of pages: 5
  - #116: M. Meinecke (Frau), number of pages: 9
  - #130: Margarete Beckel, number of pages: 4
  - #141: Gertrud von Bardeleben, number of pages: 4
  - #145: Ruth Gratwohl, number of pages: 6
  - #187: Lisi Paupie, number of pages: 22
  - #195: Maria Engelhardt, number of pages: 16
  - #207: Helene Radtke, number of pages: 14
  - #212: Maria von Belli (Freiin von Perfall), number of pages: 13
  - #244: R. Eiden, number of pages: 12
  - #297: H. Huhn (Frau), number of pages: 6
  - #305: Leokadia Kogalski, number of pages: 3
  - #353: Marta Gruse, number of pages: 10
  - #363: Erna Stoyke, number of pages: 7
  - #365: Maria Wage, number of pages: 3
  - #390: Maria Zurlinden, number of pages: 4
  - #456: Maria Wiebe, number of pages: 11
  - #457: Marianne Heimer, number of pages: 14
  - #459: Hedwig Eggert, number of pages: 11
  - #532: Erika Ullmann, number of pages: 5
  - #547: Klara L., number of pages: 5
  - #574: Gertrud Michael (geb. Moldenhauer), number of pages: 3
  - #582: Margarethe Schrimpff, number of pages: 13
  - #588: Klara Petersson (geb. Fahneb?), number of pages: 12
  - #589: Therese Diebel, number of pages: 4
- Diaries, 1930-1975
  For diaries from 1975-1981, see Incremental Materials.
  - Volume I, 1930 July 22 - 1933 March 17 (Reel 7)
    Box/Folder 13: 1
  - Appendix. European trip, 1933 June 8 - September 15
    Box/Folder 13: 2
  - Volume II, 1933 March 18 - June 7; 1933 September 16 - 1934 June 5; 1934 September 20 - 1935 May 14
    Box/Folder 13: 3
  - Appendix. European trip, 1934 June 6 - September 20 (Reel 8)
    Box/Folder 13: 4
  - Volume III, 1935 May 15 - 1936 October 11
    Box/Folder 13: 5
  - Volume IV, 1936 October 12 - 1938 January 21
    Box/Folder 13: 6
  - Volume V, 1938 February 22 - December 1
    Box/Folder 14: 1
  - Volume VI, 1938 December 2 - 1939 October 25
    Box/Folder 14: 2
  - Volume VII, 1939 November 1 - 1940 September 11 (Reel 9)
    Box/Folder 14: 3
  - Volume VIII, 1940 September 16 - 1943 June 7
    Box/Folder 14: 4
  - Volumes IX-X, 1943 June 8 - 1946 August 4
    Box/Folder 14: 5
  - Volume XI, 1949 September 20 - 1952 May 11
    Box/Folder 15: 1
  - Volume XII, 1952 June 24 - 1953 February 4 (Reel 10)
    Box/Folder 15: 2
  - Volume XIII, 1953 March 5 - 1954 September 20
    Box/Folder 15: 3
  - Volume XIV, 1954 September 28 - 1957 October 25
    Box/Folder 15: 4
  - Volume XV, 1957 November 6 - 1960 February 1
    Box/Folder 15: 5
  - Volume XVI, 1960 June 27 - 1968 June 1
    Box/Folder 15: 6
  - Volume XVII, 1958 June 16 - 1969 August 27; 1969 September 15; 1969 November 19 - 1970 July 25 (Reel 11)
    Box/Folder 16: 1
  - Volume XVIII. European trip, 1969 August 30 - October 30
    Box/Folder 16: 2
  - Volume XIX, 1971 September 1 - 1975 December 4
    Box/Folder 16: 3
- Transcriptions of Diaries, 1930-1979
  Typed transcriptions of Abel's handwritten diaries. See also: Incremental Materials.
  - Volume I, 1930 July 22 - 1933 March 17 (Reel 11)
    Box/Folder 16: 4
  - Appendix. European trip, 1933 June 8 - September 15 (Reel 12)
    Box/Folder 16: 5
  - Volume II, 1933 March 18 - June 7; 1933 September 16 - 1934 June 5; 1934 September 20 - 1935 May 14
    Box/Folder 17: 1-2
  - Appendix. European trip, 1934 June 6 - September 20
    Box/Folder 17: 3
  - Appendix. European trip, 1935 May 22 - July 8
    Box/Folder 17: 4
  - Volume III, 1935 May 15-22; 1935 July 8 - 1936 October 11
    Box/Folder 17: 5-6
  - Volume IV, 1936 October 12 - 1938 January 21 (Reel 13)
    Box/Folder 17: 7
  - Volume V, 1938 February 22 - December 1
    Box/Folder 18: 1
  - Volume VI, 1938 December 2 - 1939 October 25
    Box/Folder 18: 2
  - Volume VII, 1939 November 1 - 1940 September 11
    Box/Folder 18: 3
  - Volume VIII, 1940 September 26 - 1943 June 7
    Box/Folder 18: 4
  - Volumes IX-X, 1943 June 8 - 1946 August 4 (Reel 14)
    Box/Folder 19: 1
  - Volume XI, 1949 September 20 - 1952 May 11
    Box/Folder 19: 2
  - Volume XII, 1952 June 24 - 1953 February 4
    Box/Folder 19: 3
  - Volume XIII, 1953 March 5 - 1954 September 20
    Box/Folder 19: 4
  - Volumes XIV, 1954 September 28 - 1957 October 25
    Box/Folder 19: 5
  - Volume XV, 1957 November 6 - 1960 February 1 (Reel 15)
    Box/Folder 20: 1
  - Volume XVI, 1960 June 27 - 1968 June 1
    Box/Folder 20: 2
  - Volume XVII, 1968 June 16 - 1969 August 27; 1969 September 15; 1969 November 19 - 1970 July 25
    Box/Folder 20: 3
  - Volume XVIII, 1969 August 30 - October 30; 1970 August 1 - 1971 August 14
    Box/Folder 20: 4
  - Volume XIX, 1971 September 1 - 1975 December 4
    Box/Folder 20: 5
  - "The Coming of World War II: A Memoir Based on a Contemporary Journal." Edited diary entries, 1938-1941 (Reel 16)
    Box/Folder 20: 6
  - "The Coming of World War II: A Memoir Based on a Contemporary Journal." Edited diary entries (cont'd.), 1938-1941
    Box/Folder 21: 1
  - Volume XX, 1975 December 15 - 1979 November 11
    Box/Folder 21: 2
- Incremental Materials, 1932-1988
  Includes diaries, diary transcripts, speeches and writings, course materials, and printed matter acquired as an increment to the collection.
  - Diaries, 1975-1981
    - Volume XX, 1975 December 15 - 1979 November 22 (Reel 16)
      Box/Folder 21: 3
    - Volume XXI, 1980 February 9 - 1981 March 14 (Reel 17)
      Box/Folder 21: 4
  - Transcriptions of diaries, 1935-1984
    Includes diary transcriptions and writings composed of edited diary entries. Arranged chronologically.
    - "Reflections on Religious Faith,", undated
      Box/Folder 21: 5-6
      Selected diary entries from various dates. Includes annotations.
    - Diary fragments, 1935-1938, undated (Reels 17-18)
      Box/Folder 22: 1-2 (Folder 1 is on Reel 17, Folder 2 is on Reel 18)
      Includes entries with hand-written titles or subjects. Includes "European Trip--1935."
    - "The Coming of World War II: A Memoir Based on a Contemporary Journal"
      Edited diary entries from 1938 to 1941.
      - Introduction, undated (Reel 18)
        Box/Folder 22: 3
      - Typescript, 1938-1941
        Box/Folder 22: 4
      - Diary fragments
        Most likely used in creation of "The Coming of World War II."
        - Volume V, 1938
          Box/Folder 23: 1
        - Volume VI, 1938-1939
          Box/Folder 23: 2
        - Volume VII, 1939-1940
          Box/Folder 23: 3
        - Volume VIII, 1940-1943 (Reel 19)
          Box/Folder 23: 4
    - Fragment, 1939
      Box/Folder 23: 5
    - Volume IX, 1943 June 8 - 1946 August 4
      Box/Folder 23: 6
    - Volume XXI, 1980 February 9 - 1981 March 14
      Box/Folder 23: 7
    - Volume XXIII, 1983 March 12 - 1984 November 30
      Box/Folder 23: 8
      The last pages of this volume include photocopies of biographical material describing Abel, as well as correspondence from 1984 and 1985.
  - Speeches and writings, 1933-1986
    Includes articles, speeches, and book reviews. Includes "Yukio Mishima" by Theodora Abel, wife of Theodore Abel. Arranged chronologically.
    - Fragments, undated (Reel 20)
      Box/Folder 24: 1
    - "Comments on the Status of Sociology,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 2
    - "Excerpt From a Forthcoming Book on Social Theory,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 3
      Includes notes and clippings from 1954 and 1964.
    - Florian Znaniecki entry published in the Dictionary of American Biography, undated
      Box/Folder 24: 4
    - "International Terrorism,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 5
    - "The Nature and Function of Social Theory,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 6
      Possibly a chapter of a larger work.
    - "New Perspectives in Sociology,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 7
    - Note on writings and predictions, undated
      Box/Folder 24: 8
    - "On Behavior Maxims,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 9
    - "On Durkheim's Study of Suicide,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 10
    - "On the Future of Sociological Theory,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 11
    - "On Progress,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 12
    - "On the Relation of Means and Ends,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 13
    - "On Verifiability in Sociology,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 14
    - "Origin of the Eastern Sociological Society,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 15
    - "The Problem of Evaluation in Sociology,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 16
    - "Reflections on Free Will,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 17
    - Review of Jewish Family Solidarity: Myth or Fact? by Stanley R. Brav, undated
      Box/Folder 24: 18
    - Review of Max Weber: The Theory of Social and Economic Organization, translated by A. M. Henderson and Talcott Parsons, undated
      Box/Folder 24: 19
    - Review of Social and Cultural Dynamics by Pitirim A. Sorokin, undated
      Box/Folder 24: 20
      Review most likely written by Abel.
    - "Some Suggested Reasons for the Failure of the Search for Sociological Theory to Produce Promising Results,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 21
    - "The Story of Sociology in Brief,", undated
      Box/Folder 24: 22
    - Theoretical considerations on the nature of social groups, undated
      Box/Folder 24: 23
      Hunter College of the City University of New York, Department of Sociology, 56.20.
    - Review of Dynamic Social Research by John J. Hader and Eduard C. Lindeman, circa 1933
      Box/Folder 24: 24
    - "Comments on Dr. Howard Becker's Paper on 'The Field of Historical Sociology,'", 1935
      Box/Folder 24: 25
    - Concentration camps and Nazism, 1938-1971
      - "Postscript,", 1938
        Box/Folder 24: 26
      - "Is a Psychiatric Interpretation of the German Enigma Necessary?,", 1945
        Box/Folder 24: 27
      - Concentration camp research project, 1949-1950, undated
        Box/Folder 24: 28
      - "Genocide,", 1950
        Box/Folder 24: 29
      - Manuscript, 1964
        Box/Folder 24: 30
      - "The Nazi Movement,", 1971
        Box/Folder 24: 31
    - "Methodology,", 1939-1940
      Box/Folder 24: 32
    - Book reviews, circa 1939-1961
      Box/Folder 24: 33
    - "The Imminent War,", 1939
      Box/Folder 24: 34
    - Notes for a report before the Committee on Foreign Affairs, House of Representatives, 1939
      Box/Folder 24: 35
      See also: Note on writings and predictions (Box 24, Folder 8).
    - "On the Inapplicability of Physisism [sic] in Sociology,", 1940
      Box/Folder 24: 36
    - "The Element of Decision in the Pattern of War,", 1941
      Box/Folder 24: 37
    - "Has Hitler a Future?," speech delivered at Bard College, 1941
      Box/Folder 24: 38
    - "The Illusions of Plans for Peace" (Robert [Maclier's] opinions), circa 1941
      Box/Folder 24: 39
    - Review of The Psychology of Social Movements by Hadley Cantril, circa 1941
      Box/Folder 24: 40
    - "How Judaism Has Kept Its Identity," review of The Jewish Community by Salo Baron, 1943
      Box/Folder 24: 41
    - "Trends and Forces in European Reconstruction After War,", 1944
      Box/Folder 24: 42
    - "On the Need of Perspective in Our Relations With Russia," speech, and "Our Relations With Russia,", 1945-1946
      Box/Folder 24: 43
    - "Our Relations With Russia,", 1946 (Reel 21)
      Box/Folder 25: 1
    - Writings and notes on significance and the nature of sociology, 1948-1960
      Box/Folder 25: 2
    - Verstehen writings, 1948-1967, undated
      See also: Abstract (Box 25, Folder 35) and Course material and notes (Box 26, Folder 11).
      - "Verstehen I and Verstehen II,", undated
        Box/Folder 25: 3
      - "Verstehen: A Reexamination of Its Significance in Socio-Cultural Analyses,", undated
        Box/Folder 25: 4
      - "The Role of Verstehen,", undated
        Box/Folder 25: 5
      - "The Operation Called Verstehen,", 1948
        Box/Folder 25: 6
      - "A Reply to Professor Wax,", 1976
        Box/Folder 25: 7
    - "Comments on the Voice of America Broadcasts to Poland,", 1949
      Box/Folder 25: 8
    - "On the Nature of Science,", 1950
      Box/Folder 25: 9